Adam Faraj

faraj.9798@gmail.com, (336) 430-6178

Experienced Web Application Developer

Passionate Software Developer with experience with React, Angular, and skilled with vanilla JavaScript programming including modular and object-oriented best practices. Experience with NodeJS on the backend. Use of the Agile methodology to build software. Participated in all stages of SDLC (prototyping, design and development, content generation, coding, deployment, documentation, CI/CD). Comfortable with the use of Git, automated unit testing (Selenium), and some AWS cloud services. Continuous education in software related technologies, with relevant coursework in PHP Essentials, SQL Essentials, Java Basics, and Python Basics.

Experience

Front End Web Developer - Market America (June 2019 - Present)

- Use HTML, CSS3/SASS, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, XML, and ColdFusion for e-commerce websites.
- Edit, maintain, and deploy projects and styleguides for other developers within the company to use.
- Use Bitbucket/Stash for version control.
- Mentor and guide junior developers with web development and best practices.

Web Developer –Rural Sourcing Inc. (May 2018 - June 2019)

- Used Angular, AngularJS, CSS/SASS, JS, MongoDB, AWS, and NodeJS to build websites and web apps.
- Edited, maintained (with Git/Bitbucket), and deployed projects.
- Directly communicated with clients to achieve desired results.
- Mentored junior associate web developers with web development and best practices.

Independent Web Developer – Adam Faraj Solutions (March 2015 - Present)

- Created http://jourdainfisher.com for comedian/actor/writer Jourdain Fisher using AWS and React.
- Worked with e-commerce CMS, developing front facing store, maintaining existing infrastructure, and porting front-end code to more modern architecture.
- Worked with a local business to create an eCommerce website using Shopify.

Junior Web Developer (Contractor) – Lexo (January 2015 - March 2015)

- Worked on home page with a small team to develop updated public facing site using HTML5, CSS, and JS.
- Used BEM to manage and organize CSS modules, including language selection utility and login form.
- Brought art concepts to implementation with clean and robust HTML, CSS, and JS.

Analytical Chemist – Procter & Gamble (March 2014 - May 2018)

- Performed wet chemistry on FDA regulated products to ensure quality, as well as training new employees.
- Used SAP for data management and ensured data integrity is compliant with FDA guidelines.

Education

BS, Biology (Pre-Med) - University of North Carolina at Greensboro, 2013

• Relevant coursework: Physics I / II, and Calculus I / II / III

Interests & Activities

• Software development, computers and technology, photography, videography, music, dance, cars, travel, help teach free web development seminars at local public library